So, lately I've been getting a lot of
requests on Instagram and also on
Facebook um from people who want to know
what is the name of this big red
apparatus,
where can they get this thick bar pad?
What kinds of bands are these and where
can they get them? And so, I thought I'd
film a video describing the ideal hip
thrusting situation.
Um, I'm going to have a blog post where
I have a picture of all this stuff and I
label it and I have links to everything.
That way, uh, you you you'll have, you
know, you don't have to search for
anything. You can just go to the blog
post, which I'll have in the YouTube
video. I'll have in the description, um,
the link to the blog post, so you can
just click on all the links. Um, but
I've been hip thrusting for eight and a
half years, and not only with myself,
but prescribing it to clients. So, I
have learned a ton along the way and I
can save you a lot of time and
frustration if you watch this video. So,
who will benefit from watching this
video? Anyone who does hip thrust. Most
of you watching probably hip thrust at a
commercial gym and you know, you
probably use a bench like this and you
just use their barbell and they probably
have a crappy thick bar or a crappy bar
pad that you use or maybe you use like a
yoga mat that you fold up or something.
So, you'll benefit from learning from
some of these items that you can
purchase that are relatively
inexpensive.
But others um that are watching this
might maybe some of you are personal
trainers, maybe some of you are strength
coaches, maybe you are just a lifter who
wants to buy this for your garage so you
can hip thrust with bands, you know,
very frequently, like 5 days a week. Um
or maybe you want to buy one of these
hip thrusters for your facility. Maybe
you own a studio or own a gym and you
can buy these. So, um, everyone will
benefit from watching this. Now, uh,
first I'm going to roll through the
equipment and tell you where I bought it
and then I'll demonstrate. So, this
first piece of equipment is this big
giant red thing. This is called the hip
thruster. And I invented this because
I own this garage gym here. I wanted a
standalone unit. I don't want to take up
a power rack um, or a bench, you know? I
want the benches to be used for bench
pressing, the power ax to be used for
squatting. And this way, I can just have
a standalone unit. So, this hip thruster
doesn't move. You stand on it. You don't
have to have someone pushing up from
behind or you don't have to put this up
against a wall or up against a rack. Um,
this bench here is 18 in high. It's too
high for most people. I made this 16 in
high. And I made the padding kind of
wrap around here. Some people will hip
thrust against like pio boxes and their
backs get all scraped up. So I made sure
this cushioning is very is good. And it
also has these bags here so you can
attach bands to them. You can do band
hip thrusts in a power rack or you can
hook the bands to heavy dumbbells, but
the ideal situation is to have a hip
thruster.
And the hip thruster you can buy from
the hip thruster.com or if you're in
Europe you can buy it from uh hip
thruster.uk.com
or something like that. I have links to
those but uh um the cost in America is
$499.
Um and once again Sorex makes me for
those but you order off the hip
thruster.com.
And uh the next thing I want to talk
about is this red pad here. They make
this in blue as well. I do not make
this. I was I had every intention of
doing my own thick bar padding and
calling it like the hip thrust sponge or
something like that. But the in the uh
inventor of this squat sponge did
something nice. I started promoting it
for him and he sent me three of these.
So because of this nice gesture, I don't
become his competition even though I
could probably sell a bunch more than he
could. Um, I told him he should name it
the hip thrust sponge, not the squat
sponge, because I would use this I use
this for hip thrust all the time, but I
wouldn't use it very often for squats.
But anyway, that is purchased off of
Amazon and it's like 25 bucks. You get
it within a week. Just t go to Amazon,
type a search for squat sponge, or you
can search on Google and that'll come
up. All right, the next thing I want to
discuss is the mini bands. So, for
women, I prefer them to use these guys
here. These mini bands I bought from
Perform Better. And uh this is the
second strongest, the the blue, and then
their strongest is the black. And those
cost like three bucks or something like
that. And that's from perform
better.com. Um and we wear these around
our knees sometimes when we hip thrust
to increase the challenge onto the
glutes. For most of the women prefer to
wear these mini bands beneath their
knees. Um, some prefer to wear them
above their knees.
Now, for men, these mini bands work
fine, but for stronger men, I prefer the
hip circle. So, this hip circle, it's uh
it's made invented by Mark Bell, and
it's it's awesome. You can use this for
all sorts of things, for lateral band
walks and things like that, just like
the other mini bands, but this is just a
little sturdier and more heavy duty.
These we wear above the knees. And this
uh Rogue I I uh you can purchase this
off of Rogue and other websites, too. I
think the cost is around $25 if I'm not
mistaken.
Okay, the next item I want to talk about
is this Eric balance pad.
So,
first uh I when I first started hip
thrusting, I used for for bar padding, I
used a Hampton thick bar pad. And then I
started using this, but this became
weird because it's just so bulky. We put
the bar here. And then now I prefer the
squat sponge. So, you might be wondering
why I have this here. There are a lot of
women in general
um who do better when they sit on that
when they hook thrust. So this just
brings the brings it up a couple inches.
So if uh essentially it would be like
moving this down to 14inch height. So uh
we use this for women that are either
very short like 5'2 and under or some of
the women are actually normal height
like maybe they're like 5'5 but they
have really long legs and short torso.
So for the women who have shorter
torsos, they sit their butts on here and
then they hit thrust.
So this is again it's called an Eric's
balance pad and I bought this off from
Perform better um I think or or Amazon.
They both sell it and I think it's like
59 bucks. But they also there are
knockoffs of these that you can
investigate. I don't know the names of
them, but they look like these, but I
can't vouch for them because I've never
I don't know if they're just as good or
not because I've never used them.
Okay,
now I want to talk about these guys
here. Um, these are the long bands, and
you can get these from two different
places, Sorinex or Elite FTS. This here
is an Elite FTS band. These ones are
Sorinex, but uh I actually like the
Elite FTS band more. Um, but both of
these work better or work work really
well. Um, I think the prices of these
range from like
$10 to $30. I think this is like 30 and
this is like 10. But this is called a
strong band.
And I recommend that you buy two strong
bands. So, uh, two strong bands for the
stronger guys. Um, this is an average
band and this is a light band. And I
think their length is 22 in or
something. So, uh, the be first timers
when they do band hip dress, they might
start off with just a light. Then after
a couple weeks, they move to an average.
After month or two, almost every woman
is up to using a strong band because I I
prioritize hip thrusting.
Uh, my strongest women for the most part
use combination of they'll use the
strong uh and the average band combined
together. The stronger men will combine
two strong. So you can also pair these
bands up around your hips with the mini
bands worn around the knees which I'll
show you. And then the last thing before
I demonstrate, see these mats here?
These are an inch and a half thick.
And the reason why I have these here,
these are very important. This squat
sponge is thick. If you hip thrust
without that squat sponge, you can roll
the bar over your legs. But if you use
that squat sponge, now you're
you can't roll it over. So, I'll show
you what I'm talking about.
So,
if I just have
the bar here and I don't use any padding
at all
to get into position, I can just roll
this over my legs like that.
But because
I'm using a squat sponge,
this can't fit over this can't fit over
my legs right here. hits and I can't get
into position. So, what works really
well here is to just have these little
guys. And it's funny cuz all this is
this is the same thing as this guy right
here,
the little foot mat for the hip
thruster. I just had Sorex send me two
of them.
But there is a flooring company that
makes these. You might be able to make
these by yourself out of uh plywood or
something. You could just cut plywood
and use wood glue to glue them together.
Or uh some people use bumper plates or
just plates uh 45 lb plates to put next
to them. But it's it makes your life so
much easier when you hip thrust,
especially when you use this squat
sponge. One thing I will tell you, if
you don't have thick bar padding, and
you just have it against your pelvis,
the bar, where it's like a flimsy
padding, it hurts. And because of that
pain, pain shuts down muscle activation.
So, you can't get the best hip thrusting
workout. So, if you're in any pain, it's
not going to you're automatically not
going to be able to develop the glutes
as much. So, this essentially helps you
get a better glute workout. So, here's
what it looks like.
I roll the bar over. I get into place
from here.
See how this ends up being
perfect fit.
Get into place
and
hip th.
Now
if you want to use
the these guys
for the women
they will put these
right here
and they will go like this.
Okay. We even do burnout methods where
you combine the bands. So here I'll show
you
how to do
the body.
We do different burnout methods.
So here you can do two bands at the same
time like this.
Now,
for me,
that's actually
this black mini band and this blue
strong band
is good to use for women to do for like
sets of 20 reps, 20 to 30. This is what
we use for most of my athletic, stronger
women. But for strong men,
I actually use
this hip circle
and I put it just above the knees like
this.
And I will use
two bands.
As you'll see here, this is not easy for
me.
[Music]
[Applause]
This gets the same level of activation
um you know that a heavy barbell hip
thrust does. Very similar. So, what's
nice is if
you didn't have any plates, no barbells,
if you just hip thrusted out of your
garage or your say you have a spare
bedroom. And actually, this here
can fold up and fit in the hip thruster
can fold up and fit in a closet or it
can kind of roll under a bed so that
just this is sticking out. So, it
doesn't take up a lot of space. Let's
say you didn't even have a barbell. You
didn't have a thick bar pad. You didn't
have any plates, no collars. All you
had, and you wouldn't need these guys
either. All you have is a hip thruster,
uh, hip circle or mini bands, and these
long bands.
Watch how awesome of a workout I can get
just from doing this here.
So, if I do, you know, sets of 12 like
that and I do three sets of 12, it's an
amazing glute workout. And you don't
even need any plates. Um, so the last
thing I want to show you is how you can
kind of combine everything if you
wanted.
So
if you wanted to, you could do
could have all this at the same time
like this.
Now I've got
barbell
bands around the hips and bands around
the knees.
[Applause]
So
That's
another option.
And then when I mentioned the burnouts
earlier,
um sometimes we'll go like this and just
do like
20 reps of these
right into 20 reps of these right into
for a total of 60 total reps.
So again,
uh tons of options here depending what
your goals are. If you're just looking
for glute hypertrophy,
then you can do a variety of rep ranges.
If you're looking for, you know,
transfer to a sport or transfer to
powerlifting, I would recommend lower
rep ranges, going heavier with the
barbell.
But for
glute hypertrophy, what we've been doing
with my clients is at the end of every
session, they do their heavy stuff,
their heavy squats, their heavy
deadlifts, heavy, you know, hip thrusts,
all these other exercise they do at the
end of the workout. We use the bands to
just get a burnout and they'll do like
five minutes at the end of the workout
with band hip thrust and uh so that when
they leave the session with a huge burn,
a huge pump in their glutes and uh you
know I usually get a text message from
my clients on their way home saying, "Oh
my god, my glutes are still on fire." So
again, I hope this video has been
beneficial to you. I will have all the
links on my blog which I will link in
the description of this video.